# **RAYMOND S. USBAL**

## +6344.9402440

raymond@philippinedev.com

242 Ipil cor. Epifanio Sts. Santolan, Palayan City Philippines

#### **Profile**

I am looking for work where I can contribute my well-rounded skills in web development. I have 8 years of web programming experience. I have use PHP, Python and a little bit of Ruby. I can also write Bash scripts. I have also developed a personal project in Swift for the iPhone, the Parallel Bible App, with a demo on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcG80vO5oFg">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcG80vO5oFg</a>

# **Latest PHP Project**

https://github.com/rusbal/names-of-jesus

http://jesus.philippinedev.com/login

Test user: john@doe.com

Password: johndoe

This is a collaboration tool for writing a book. The authors can save as many revisions as they want. They can also add comments that are visible to the other authors. They can view the revision of other authors as well. A PDF can be generated from the content.

#### **Github**

https://github.com/rusbal

# **Bitbucket**

https://bitbucket.org/rusbal/

## **Experience**

Freelance Web Developer - 2012-Present

Wordpress Development, Linux Server Administration, Cloudflare DNS

PHP Developer / System Administrator, Maxiprint — 2010-2012 Maintenance of and e-commerce web store.

Freelance Web Developer — 2009-2010 Varied LAMP web project assignments.

PHP Developer, Bluefrog Mobile — 2006-2009 Programmed in-house web apps written in LAMP.

#### Education

Polytechnic University of the Philippines — Bachelor in Business Administration, 2008

**Skills** 

I have used the following Linux distros: Arch, Centos, Fedora, OpenSuSE and Debian. Currently using Ubuntu and Mac OSX. I have used MySQL and Postgresql.

## Selected Reviews:

Raymond is a strong and experienced developer, with excellent analytical skills and good OO design patterns. He can build well-architected systems from the ground up. He can be trusted to produce high-quality OO PHP5 code. His SQL queries are solid. His code is readable and maintainable. His UI sense is top notch, a rare quality for the strong backend coder he is. He is honest and trustworthy. I wholeheartedly endorse his output.

Michel G. Thouati, Ph.D. (France)

Raymond is a unique programmer who combines project management skills, indepth coding knowledge, clear communication and above all a great work ethic and honesty which is critical when working across different continents and timezones. We have used Raymond extensively to help build the lending and borrowing applications and systems that drive the Lending Hub peer to peer loans website. We recommend Raymond and his team to business owners and webmasters who are looking for someone who can code the fine detail but also help you manage your project.

Ivan Mantelli (Australia)